Guide to the postcard album 'Egypt and Palestine' from the Hisham Khatib Collection AD.MC.030_ref164
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
'Egypt and Palestine' postcard album - Hisham Khatib Collection
1910s-1920s
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Khatib, Hisham, Mr.
Unknown
AD.MC.030_ref164
40
94 Photographic Prints 94 postcards over 50 pages of an album
Generally good, some brittle and warped.
E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164
Content Description
Digital surrogates of 2,980 photographs and postcards (both individual prints and contained within albums) focused on the Near East, including the Holy Lands, Palestine, Jordan, Turkey, Syria and Egypt as well as a very small number from Europe. Many of the photographers or studios are identified, some are unknown.
Palestine; Jordan; Egypt; Religious Sites; Landscapes; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Postcards; Khatib, Hisham, Mr.
- The front cover of the album "Egypt and Palestine" with floral embossing., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000001; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  English Writing; Egypt; Palestine
- The inside front cover of the Album "Egypt and Palestine.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000002; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Egypt; Palestine
- From the top down: A postcard of the Ras-El-Tin Lighthouse, a hand-colored postcard of the Ramleh Station in Alexandria, and a postcard of Mehemet-Ali Palace and Mansheya Square in Alexandria., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000003; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Lighthouses; Electricity; Trams; Transportation; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Coast; Water; Beaches; Boats/Ships; Men; Shops; Buildings; Alexandria, Egypt; Horses; Carriages/Coaches; Women; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Monuments/Memorials; Signs/Signposts; Animals
- Top: A hand-colored postcard of Pompey's Pillar and the Sphinx in Alexandria. Bottom: a postcard of Fairhaven Hotel in Palais Ramleh, Alexandria., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000004; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Monuments/Memorials; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Alexandria, Egypt; Men; Buildings; Hotels; French Writing
- From the top down: a postcard of the Fairhaven Hotel in Palais Ramleh, Alexandria; a postcard showing a general view of the harbor at Port Said; and (No.333) a hand-colored postcard of ships in the Suez Canal., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000005; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); Carl Andelfinger & Co, München; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Buildings; Hotels; Port Said, Egypt; Alexandria, Egypt; French Writing; Ports; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Canals; Deserts; Flags
- From the top down: a hand-colored postcard of men by tents in the desert; a hand-colored postcard of a man ploughing with cattle; and a postcard of a group of people crossing a bridge with a camel, with a man riding a donkey in the background., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000006; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Palm Trees; Agriculture/Farms; Landscapes; Tents; Mountains/Hills; Regional/National Dress; Irrigation; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Individual Portraits; Cattle/Cows; Animals; Transportation; Machines; Camels; Group Portraits; Donkeys; Men; Countryside/Rural
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of a women on a carriage and a man standing in Egypt. Bottom: [No.66] a hand-colored postcard of a man and a woman with a donkey., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000007; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Regional/National Dress; Niqab/Burqa; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Deserts; Animals; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; French Writing; Egypt; Men; Group Portraits; Donkeys; Palm Trees; Buildings; Head Covers/Veils
- From the top down: a man guiding a camel over a bridge, a hand-colored postcard of people beside the Nile, and a hand-colored postcard of boats on the bank of the Nile., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000008; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Egypt; Nile River; Rivers; Water; Bridges; Palm Trees; Buildings; Camels; Men; Regional/National Dress; Individual Portraits; Niqab/Burqa; Boys; Children; Sheep; Animals; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Coast; Trains
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of a group of people sitting under a date palm (Equipage Égyptien). Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of a family with a camel and donkey., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000009; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Palm Trees; Egypt; Men; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Mosques; Architecture; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Camels; Animals; Facial Hair; Religious Sites; Pilgrims; French Writing
- Top: a painted postcard of a street in Egypt. Bottom: a painted postcard of women and a boy in an alleyway., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000010; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Paintings; Postcards; Mosques; Streets/Roads; Religious Sites; Crowds; Donkeys; Animals; Egypt; Shops; Street Vendors; Men; Regional/National Dress; Women; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Buildings
- From the top down: A postcard of a group walking near a town on the banks of the Nile, a hand-colored postcard of boys and men with water buffalos in the Nile during a flood, and a hand-colored postcard of a man and a boy working with sugarcane., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000011; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paintings; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Nile River; Rivers; Water; Egypt; Men; Boys; Children; Animals; Group Portraits; Camels; Cattle/Cows; Coast; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Buildings; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Streets/Roads; Street Vendors; Workers; Hats; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; French Writing
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of a group of water carriers, Cairo. Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of a woman seated with two scribes., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000012; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Paintings; Postcards; Group Portraits; Men; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Workers; Water; Women; Niqab/Burqa; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair; Shops; Cairo, Egypt
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of a man holding a smoking pipe/shisha in regional dress (Fumeur de Hachiche). Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of a carriage and two men walking in front of it in Saïs, Egypt., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000013; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Men; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Smoking; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Cairo, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Horses; Transportation; Carriages/Coaches; Buildings; Palm Trees; French Writing
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of two people in front of an ornate doorway in Egypt. Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of Sheikh el-Anwar's house, Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000014; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Paintings; Postcards; Doors/Entrances; Architecture; Buildings; Men; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Cairo, Egypt; Signatures; French Writing; Houses; Girls; Head Covers/Veils
- A hand-colored postcard of a woman from Cairo wearing regional dress., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000015; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Women; Niqab/Burqa; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Individual Portraits; French Writing; Jewelry; Cairo, Egypt
- From the top down: a hand-colored postcard of a caravan of camels near the Great Pyramids, a view of the City of the Dead and the Mosque of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaytbay, and a hand-colored postcard of the Mosque-Madrassa of Sultan Hassan and Al-Rifa'i Mosque., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000016; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Mosques; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Religious Sites; Landscapes; Tombs/Mausoleums; Cairo, Egypt; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Camels; Animals; Deserts
- Top: a postcard of the City of the Dead and the Funerary Complex of Sultan al-Ashraf Barsbay. Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of the Aqsunqur Mosque (Blue Mosque) in Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000017; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Tombs/Mausoleums; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Horses; Animals; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Women; Children; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Cameras; Mosque and Tomb of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaitbay; French Writing
- A blank page in the Album "Egypt and Palestine.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000018; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
- From the top down: a view of the Shahin Al-Khalwati mosque, and two views of tombs and mausoleums in the Southern Cemetery, City of the Dead, Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000019; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Tombs/Mausoleums; Monasteries/Convents; Mountains/Hills; Deserts; Cairo, Egypt; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Mokattam, Cairo, Egypt
- Three views of the road leading to the Great Pyramids of Giza., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000020; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Giza, Egypt; Trams; Streets/Roads; Transportation; Pyramids; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Men; Women; Boats/Ships; Railways; Bridges; Buildings; Water; Rivers; Landscapes
- Three views of the Great Pyramids of Giza., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000020; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paintings; Pyramids; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Water; Palm Trees; Rivers; Landscapes; Giza, Egypt; Camels; Men; Group Portraits; Animals; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
- Three views of the Great Pyramids of Giza., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000021; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Pyramids; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Deserts; Architecture; Men; Camels; Animals; Giza, Egypt
- Three views of the Great Sphinx of Giza., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000022; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Giza, Egypt; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Deserts; Landscapes; Architecture; Pyramids; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Camels; Animals; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- From the top down: a hand-colored postcard of the Church of the Epiphany in Port Said, a landscape of Al Qantara, and a hand-colored postcard showing a panoramic view of Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000023; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Port Said, Egypt; Churches; Religious Sites; Architecture; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Forts/Castles; Postcards; Buildings; El-Qantara el-Sharqîya, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Water; Transportation; Ports; Camels; Men; Animals; Women; Children; Head Covers/Veils; Palm Trees; Cairo, Egypt; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; Mountains/Hills; French Writing
- Two views of boats on the Nile river. The top is a postcard showing a dahabeya and the bottom is a painting of a felucca., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000024; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Paintings; Men; Regional/National Dress; Water; Giza, Egypt; Rivers; Pyramids; Architecture; Palm Trees; Nile River; French Writing
- Three hand-colored postcards from the top down: two feluccas on the Nile, (No. 36) the Aswan Dam, and a boat on the Nile., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000025; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dams/Barrages; Water; Nile River; Rivers; Aswan, Egypt; French Writing; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Boats/Ships; Buildings; Palm Trees; Transportation
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of the obelisk at Heliopolis. Bottom: a painting of an alleyway., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000026; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paintings; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Donkeys; Animals; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Regional/National Dress; Egypt
- From the top down: a hand-colored postcard of a caravan, a hand-colored postcard of the harbor and Maison Hollandaise in Port Said, and drawings of ancient Egyptians on leather., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000027; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Streets/Roads; Camels; Animals; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Port Said, Egypt; Ports; Buildings; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; French Writing
- Top: a painting of the Great Sphinx of Giza. Bottom: a postcard of the entrance to the canal at Port Said., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000028; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paintings; English Writing; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Pyramids; Ports; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Flags; Palm Trees; Port Said, Egypt; Giza, Egypt; Buildings
- Top: a view of three feluccas sailing during sunset. Bottom: a postcard of the National Hotel on Suleyman Pasha Street (now Talaat Harb Street), Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000029; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Boats/Ships; Water; Nile River; Rivers; Transportation; Streets/Roads; Hotels; Cairo, Egypt; Horses; Carriages/Coaches; Animals; Street Lamps
- Top: (No. 893) a hand-colored postcard of a group of men making a fire. Bottom: (No.776) a hand-colored postcard of women and children in a village., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000030; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  French Writing; Italian Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Photographic Prints; Postcards; English Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Water; Countryside/Rural; Palm Trees; Children; Men; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Egypt
- From the top down: a postcard of the Channel Company offices in Port Said, (No.6) a postcard of the Qasr-El-Nil Bridge in Cairo and a hand-colored postcard of Zahlé and Mount Lebanon., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000031; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Zahle, Beqaa, Lebanon; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Bridges; Palm Trees; Men; Nile River; Cairo, Egypt; Street Lamps; Electricity; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Ports; Port Said, Egypt; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Cars/Trucks; French Writing; English Writing
- A painting of people selling bread at a market., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000032; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Paintings; Group Portraits; Men; Children; Women; Facial Hair; Regional/National Dress; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Food; Street Vendors; Workers; Markets; Egypt
- A painted postcard of people on a hillside in the Upper Kidron Valley., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000033; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Paintings; Postcards; Men; Regional/National Dress; Kidron Valley; Group Portraits
- From the top down: verso of a postcard, a postcard of the Tombs of the Kings in Jerusalem, and a hand-colored postcard of a man carrying water in a village near Cairo., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000034; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Palm Trees; Countryside/Rural; Jerusalem; Tombs/Mausoleums; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Religious Sites; Bridges; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Individual Portraits; French Writing; German Writing
- A panoramic postcard of the Dome of the Rock and Al-Aqsa Compound., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000034_002; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  German Writing; Postcards; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Al-Aqsa Mosque/al-Masjid al-ʾAqṣā; Jerusalem; Men; Priests/Clergymen; Buildings; Architecture; Mountains/Hills
- Top: (No.2) a hand-colored postcard showing an interior view of the Pool of Bethesda. Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of the Gate of Judgement (Seventh Station) in the Via Dolorosa., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000035; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Religious Sites; Jerusalem; French Writing; German Writing; Men; Streets/Roads; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Group Portraits
- Top: (No.18) a hand-colored postcard of St. Stephen's Gate (Lions' Gate) in Jerusalem Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of the Fifth Station of the Via Dolorosa., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000036; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Jerusalem; Religious Sites; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Men; Boys; Children; Facial Hair; Hats; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits
- Top: a painted postcard of the front courtyard of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre. Bottom: (No.3) a hand-colored postcard of the ruins of St. Anne's Church near the Pool of Bethesda., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000037; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paintings; Postcards; Religious Sites; Jerusalem; Street Vendors; Churches; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Men; Markets; French Writing; German Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of a crowd in the courtyard of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre. Bottom: a hand-colored postcard of a general view of Jerusalem and the Jerusalem Railway Station., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000038; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Crowds; Religious Sites; Churches; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Streets/Roads; Jerusalem; Mountains/Hills; Railways; Transportation; Carriages/Coaches; Horses; Animals; Landscapes; Buildings; Street Vendors; Signatures
- From the top down: a hand-colored postcard of the Church of the Dormition, a hand-colored postcard showing the landscape of Siloam (Silwan), and (No.10) a postcard of oil lamps in a museum near St. Anne's Church, Jerusalem (including a Biblical reference)., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000039; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; French Writing; German Writing; Religious Sites; Churches; Buildings; Architecture; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Siloam/Silwan; Mount Zion/Jabal Sahyoun, Jerusalem; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Museums; Lanterns/Lamps
- Three hand-colored postcards from the top down: a group of tinsmiths in their shop in Cairo, the Avenue of the Sphinxes in Luxor, and a landscape of Raouché (Pigeons' Rock), Beirut., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000040; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Men; Boys; Workers; Group Portraits; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Street Vendors; Lanterns/Lamps; Cairo, Egypt; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Streets/Roads; Mountains/Hills; Palm Trees; Animals; Water; Seas; Beirut, Lebanon; Luxor, Egypt; French Writing
- Top: a postcard of the Tree of Virgin Mary in Al Matariyyah, Cairo. Bottom: a postcard of a painting of two men in regional dress, caption is verse Micah 7:14., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref164_000041; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_030_ref164)